Oh no, I think I included too much information
in my presentation
I won’t be able to finish it in the time I have
How much time do you have for your presentation?
The average length is usually about twenty minutes
I only have fifteen minutes
And I have a lot more to say than that
You need to do a good job managing the time
Look at your structure outlines
plan a schedule accordingly
and allocate time into each section
OK. Now I see what my problem is
I wrote too much for the introduction
How do I adjust it?
I suggest you rehearse your talk first
and find out how much talking time
you are using for each section
Isn’t that called a “timed rehearsal”?
Do I need a timekeeper or a stopwatch
to keep track of time?
Yes. Time each section carefully
If you’re talking time is longer than the allotted time
adjust your script.
Right. You need to be flexible
For example, if you really need more time
for an explanation and examples in the body
make the opening and ending shorter
If the presentation becomes too long
the audience will lose interest by the end
I know I need to keep the whole presentation
within the given time
Another tip for good time management
is to always start on time
I know a lot of presentations go over
their allotted time just because they start late
Right, and remember, even with the best preparation
something unexpected might occur during the presentation
And that will extend the overall program
Try to keep to the time and be ready to adapt
A written schedule can help you keep track of time easily
It’s quite effective and efficient in helping you
to convey your ideas in the allocated time
Wow, look at the time. I’d better go
I enjoyed talking with you.